It's not a diary, it's a movie.
Diary of a Wimpy Kid is a comedy, family film directed by Thor Freudenthal.
Greg Heffley is headed for big things, but first he has to survive the scariest,
most humiliating experience of any kid’s life – middle school!
That won’t be easy, considering he’s surrounded by hairy-freckled morons,
wedgie-loving bullies and a moldy slice of cheese with nuclear cooties!
Greg Heffley, played by Zachary Gordon.
Rowley Jefferson, played by Robert Capron.
Frank J. Heffley, played by Steve Zahn.
Rodrick Heffley, played by Devon Bostick.
Susan Heffley, played by Rachael Harris.
Angie Steadman, played by Chloë Grace Moretz.
Diary of a Wimpy Kid is a 2010 American comedy film directed by Thor
Freudenthal and based on Jeff Kinney's 2007 book of the same name.
The film stars Zachary Gordon, Robert Capron, Devon Bostick,
Rachael Harris, Steve Zahn, and Chloë Grace Moretz.
20th Century Fox released the film theatrically in the United States on March 19, 2010, receiving mixed
reviews from critics and grossing $76 million worldwide against a $15 million budget.
The film spawned a film franchise and was followed by three sequels:
Rodrick Rules (2011), Dog Days (2012), and The Long Haul (2017).
An animated reboot of the same name was released in 2021, which was followed by three sequels of its own: a second adaptation of
Rodrick Rules (2022), Diary of a Wimpy Kid Christmas: Cabin Fever (2023), and Diary of a Wimpy Kid: The Last Straw (2025).
A book detailing the film's creation process, titled The Wimpy
Kid Movie Diary, was released on March 16, 2010.
The film explores themes of cheese, coming of age, breaking
the fourth wall, young boy, middle school.
The tone is lighthearted.